<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Christian on Jiyu</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/christian/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Christian on Jiyu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2022 22:57:54 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/christian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The word &#39;Word&#39; in Bible </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/christian-bible-words/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/christian-bible-words/</guid>
      <description>In the beginning was the Word, and the Word was with God, and the Word was God. John 1:1 (ESV)&#xA;And God said, “Let there be light,” and there was light. Genesis 1:3 NIV&#xA;Therefore this is what the LORD says: “If you repent, I will restore you that you may serve me; if you utter worthy, not worthless, words, you will be my spokesman. Jeremiah 15:19 NIV&#xA;Then Jesus looked up and said, “Father, I thank you that you have heard me.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mom, let me take the blame for Dad&#39;s mistakes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/christian-let-me-take-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/christian-let-me-take-it/</guid>
      <description>Dad shared such a little story recently.&#xA;The couple quarrelled, and the child ran around and found out: you two are not fighting again!&#xA;He ran to his dad, &amp;ldquo;Dad, dad, you just apologize to mom, you guys make up!&amp;rdquo; Dad sighed sadly and shook his head, &amp;ldquo;Your mom is not even talking to me right now.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;The child rushed to mom&amp;rsquo;s side again, &amp;ldquo;Mom, mom, you make up with dad, dad is not coming to talk now, but I know his heart is weeping!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My story with God</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/christian-testimony/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/christian-testimony/</guid>
      <description>When I was in university in China, for a while I was not busy, and interested in dreams. In my lucid dreams, I knew I was in a dream, I could have keys in my hands by just thinking of keys, and the feeling of keys in my dream was the same as in reality. I felt there’s something beyond this material world, and couldn’t stop reading the next book, new age, Buddhism, psychology, etc.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We love because He first loved us, not meaningless self love</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/christian-god-loved-us-not-self-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/christian-god-loved-us-not-self-love/</guid>
      <description>Self-esteem, self-love, self-help, self-respect, self, self, self.&#xA;You can&amp;rsquo;t love others properly without loving yourself at first. - popular idea&#xA;We love because He first loved us. 1 John 4: 19&#xA;Mental states do not come before language nor accompany a sequence of words but are lived and experienced in the context of linguistic expression. -Wittgenstein&#xA;It&amp;rsquo;s wrong from a syntax perspective at first. Help, love, respect, and care, when we use these words, they are usually correctly used to describe the relationship between people.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oral history of two Christians in a Chinese labour camp in the 1960s</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/christian-1960-camps/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/christian-1960-camps/</guid>
      <description>The Great Chinese famine from 1959 to 1961 in China killed 15 to 55 million people.&#xA;In those years, many intellectuals were sent to a re-education labour camp in Jiabiangou, Gansu province. People ate everything they could and couldn&amp;rsquo;t eat, some couldn&amp;rsquo;t even go outside to defecate, and could only pull it on their frozen bed. Tree bark was eaten up and some people ate human corpses. Some people were deliberately buried very shallow, so they were easily dug out to be eaten at night.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
