<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>China on Jiyu</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/china/</link>
    <description>Recent content in China on Jiyu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2022 22:54:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/china/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The story of a Shenzhen worker in 2000</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/share-made-in-shenzhen/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/share-made-in-shenzhen/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s from a Chinese podcast Story FM 故事FM, Episode 664, they invite people to tell their own real-life stories. I have been given permission for translation and publication here.&#xA;Shenzhen is one of the largest cities in China, and most made-in-China electronics come from Shenzhen.&#xA;Original page (WeChat) contains many pictures at that time, this is a translated version.&#xA;In 1998, I graduated from junior high school and wanted to go out to work, but my mother wouldn&amp;rsquo;t let me.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shadian, a war between Communists and Muslims in China 1975</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/story-shadian/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/story-shadian/</guid>
      <description>During the Cultural Revolution, communists were supposed to eliminate all religious and old cultures, including Confucious, Christianity, Buddism, and Muslim as well.&#xA;The communist army put pigs&amp;rsquo; heads in the Muslim community&amp;rsquo;s well. The tension kept growing, the Muslim elite from Shadian went to Beijing to talk about the situation with communist leaders, and when they came back they knew the situation was going to be worse. Obviously, they felt what was going to happen, one of the elites begged their Muslim people to send women and children out, but people were so angry and refused and thought he has betrayed them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oral history of two Christians in a Chinese labour camp in the 1960s</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/christian-1960-camps/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/christian-1960-camps/</guid>
      <description>The Great Chinese famine from 1959 to 1961 in China killed 15 to 55 million people.&#xA;In those years, many intellectuals were sent to a re-education labour camp in Jiabiangou, Gansu province. People ate everything they could and couldn&amp;rsquo;t eat, some couldn&amp;rsquo;t even go outside to defecate, and could only pull it on their frozen bed. Tree bark was eaten up and some people ate human corpses. Some people were deliberately buried very shallow, so they were easily dug out to be eaten at night.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Documentaries about China</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/tip-documentary/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/tip-documentary/</guid>
      <description>Recommended, with English subtitle 棒！少年 Tough out&#xA;豆瓣 IMDB Youtube 废城 Ghost Town&#xA;IMDB 豆瓣 Youtube 矿民、马夫、尘肺病 Miners, Groom, Pneumoconiosis 8.7&#xA;Published in 2019, 10 years with illegal miners in China&#xA;豆瓣 IMDB Youtube 算命 Fortune Teller 9.0&#xA;Ture village life through a fortune teller&#xA;豆瓣 IMDB Youtube 高三 Senior year 8.4&#xA;The most important exam in China that can determine a lifetime&#xA;豆瓣 IMDB Youtube 书记 The Transition Period 8.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The world is far from God, close to China</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/opinion-china-eng/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/opinion-china-eng/</guid>
      <description>Appreciate Peter&amp;rsquo;s help.&#xA;The ignoble are the wisest, the noble are the stupidest. These sayings are the essence of Mao Zedong&amp;rsquo;s thought, for the majority of Chinese to live by, the formation of the present China.&#xA;Basically, the evolution of the Zhuxia(Huaxia, Chinese) civilization is a deteriorating change: from the Spring and Autumn, the Warring States to the Qin and Han dynasties, and then through the Wei, Jin, Sui, Tang, Song, Yuan, Ming and Qing dynasties, we can clearly see a trend: the backbone of society such as nobles, clans, etc.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
