<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Psychology on Jiyu</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/psychology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Psychology on Jiyu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2022 21:52:58 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/psychology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Personality types don&#39;t exist,  life is not a matching game</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/opinion-personality/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/opinion-personality/</guid>
      <description>God did not create people with a predetermined type of introversion, extroversion or ABCD, unlike someone who is born with a sweet tooth and someone who likes salty, people have the freedom to choose understanding-based behaviour. The so-called most introverted person also desires friends, and the so-called most extroverted person enjoys solitude at some point. Personality types do not exist or do not exist outside of language. Even though people may exhibit personalities and characteristics, it needs to be interpreted in the concrete real world, not determined by internal mechanisms hypothesized by artificial concepts.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dangerous words, why psychology is impossible</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/opinion-words-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/opinion-words-psychology/</guid>
      <description>“But profound as psychology is, it&amp;rsquo;s a knife that cuts both ways (&amp;hellip;). I have purposely resorted to this method, gentlemen of the jury, to show that you can prove anything by it. It all depends on who makes use of it. Psychology lures even most serious people into romancing, and quite unconsciously.” ― Fyodor Dostoyevsky, The Brothers Karamazov&#xA;“The confusion and barrenness of psychology is not to be explained by calling it a “young science”; its state is not comparable with that of physics, for instance, in its beginnings&amp;hellip; For in psychology there are experimental methods and conceptual confusion&amp;hellip; The existence of the experimental method makes us think we have the means of solving the problems which trouble us; though problem and method pass one another by” (Ludwig Wittgenstein, Philosophical Investigations, 1968, II xiv, 232e).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We love because He first loved us, not meaningless self love</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/christian-god-loved-us-not-self-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/christian-god-loved-us-not-self-love/</guid>
      <description>Self-esteem, self-love, self-help, self-respect, self, self, self.&#xA;You can&amp;rsquo;t love others properly without loving yourself at first. - popular idea&#xA;We love because He first loved us. 1 John 4: 19&#xA;Mental states do not come before language nor accompany a sequence of words but are lived and experienced in the context of linguistic expression. -Wittgenstein&#xA;It&amp;rsquo;s wrong from a syntax perspective at first. Help, love, respect, and care, when we use these words, they are usually correctly used to describe the relationship between people.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5-love-languages and Extrovert only exist in our language</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/opinion-extrovert/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/opinion-extrovert/</guid>
      <description>The craving for generality is a philosophical sin.&#xA;Everyone is born with some difference. Features like hair colour, and sports/music gifts, likes salt/sweet, exist and don&amp;rsquo;t change much according to context, they are self-determined.&#xA;Obviously, there are people who are generally more talkative, and friendly to strangers and people who probably don&amp;rsquo;t talk much. Nobody denies that. By observing these things in real life, we created the concept of introvert and extrovert.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
